Calculation of a Six Sigma Performance Baseline
Welcome to this session on establishing baselines.
What we’re looking at here, is that we have several CTQ’s.
CTQ 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5.
Now, with respect to each of these CTQ’s, there is a unit of product.
Each unit of product produced, where rows shows units.
So, we have unit 1, unit 2, 3, 4, 5, and so on.
Now, in this instance of unit 1, we can see that it has five CTQ’s.
Thus, every unit produced has the same number of CTQ’s
and the same identical CTQ’s.
Also, there is one opportunity for each type of CTQ.
What we’re seeing tabulated is the outcome of production.
In other words, we have five CTQ’s in unit 1, all five passed.
If we saw a one, say for example, in cell location C11.
If there was a one, that is to say that CTQ was defective.
But since we observe a zero, in this particular cell.
Right there, since we observed zero, then we know that it was a pass.
Now, how do we get that?
If we go directly up to the yellow, we see Sigma capability.
This is the short-term capability for each of the corresponding CTQ’s.
So for CTQ 1, we see that it has a short-term capability of Three Sigma.
That converts to a yield of 93.32%.
We define that by the equation normsdist of C6,
which is three Sigma minus 1.5.
We subtract the 1.5 to convert the short-term Sigma to a long-term yield,
which is 93.32%.
So, for each of the five CTQ’s, we start with an assumption of three Sigma capability.
Where each CTQ has a yield of 93.32%.
If we hit F9, we can initiate the simulation, as many times as we would like.
What we will be doing in the simulation is producing 1000 units of product.
Where each unit of product, has the five CTQ’s.
And we are looking at the inspection and test outcome for each of those CTQ’s.
If I see a zero in column I,
then I know at least one of the CTQ’s did not conform to standard.
Now, let's look at how we got the simulation.
We have, If a uniform random number between zero and one,
is less than the defect rate, one minus C7,
then print a 1, otherwise print zero.
Thus, if the random number is less than one minus the yield,
then I see a defective.
A defective CTQ. In this case, CTQ 1 is defective.
Now, in the result I say, if some of C11 to G11, which is from here to here.
C11 to G11.
If that sum is equal to zero, then a 1, that's to say it would be a yield.
So, I want to create a counter for yield conditions, for all 1000.
And you can see if hitting F9,
I can replicate the thousand over and over.
Now, we come up to cell location B3, and we see the output.
Hitting F9, changing it.
In this case, I have 695 ones.
In other words, I had 695 cases, units,
in which all CTQ’s passed, out of a thousand.
That would be a throughput yield of 69.5%,
which converts to 92.98% per CTQ.
We find that, by taking the throughput yield, raising it to one over the number of CTQ’s.
Converting the normalized yield to Sigma, using normsinv
of the normalized yield, and then adding back the 1.5 Sigma shift.
We see the overall Sigma,
or the kind of like an average Sigma capability per CTQ.
So, this is the aggregate that has been normalized.
Running our simulation over and over, we can see that it's Three Sigma.
Which we would expect, because all of the inputs was Three Sigma.
Again, looking at the Sigma capability.
Looking at that Sigma capability constantly changing,
2.99, 3.02, 2.94. As we see that Sigma capability change,
the average will come out, over many, many cycles,
to exactly Three Sigma. Which we would expect.
This is one of the ways that we can perform simulation,
in this case we have simulated the baseline of a particular process.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.